<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>Compromise resolutions of the Hon. Henry Clay: introduced by him into the Senate of the United States, January 29th, 1850.</title>
				<author>Clay, Henry, 1777-1852</author>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<p>Published by California Historical Society.</p>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Compromise resolutions of the Hon. Henry Clay: introduced by him into the Senate of the United States, January 29th, 1850, Broadsides, Vault B-035, California Historical Society.</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<p>COMPROMISE RESOLUTIONS OF THE HON. HENRY CLAY, INTRODUCED BY HIM INTO THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES, JANUARY 29th, 1850.</p>
			<p>PREAMBLE.—It being desirable for the peace, concord and harmony of the, Union of these States, to settle and adjust amicably all questions of controversy between them arising out of the institution of Slavery, upon a fair equality and just basis—therefore—</p>
			<p>First—RESOLVED, That California, with suitable boundaries, ought, upon her application, to be admitted as one of the States of this Union, without the imposition by Congress of any restriction to the exclusion or introduction of Slavery within those boundaries.</p>
			<p>2d—RESOLVED, That as Slavery does not exist by law, and is not likely to be introduced into any of the territory acquired by the United States from the Republic of Mexico, it is inexpedient for Congress to provide, by law, either for its introduction into, or its exclusion from, any part of the said territory ; and that appropriate territorial Governments ought to be established, by Congress, in all of the said territory not assigned as the boundaries of the proposed State of California, without the addition of any restriction or condition on the subject of Slavery.</p>
			<p>3d—RESOLVED, That the Western boundary of the State of Texas ought to be ﬁxed on the Rio del Norte, commencing one marine league from its mouth, and running up that river to the southern line of New Mexico, thence with that line Eastwardly, and continuing in the same direction, to the line as established between the United States and Spain, excluding any portion of New Mexico, whether lying on the East or West of that river.</p>
			<p>4th—RESOLVED, That it be proposed to the State of Texas, that the United States will provide for the payment of all that portion of all the legitimate and bona ﬁde public debts of that State contracted prior to its annexation to the United States, and for which the duties on foreign imports were pledged by the said State to its creditors, not exceeding the sum of ------ dollars, in consideration of the duties, as pledged, having been no longer applicable to that object after the said annexation, but having thenceforward become payable to the United States, and upon the condition also that the said State shall by some solemn and authentic act of her Legislature, or of a convention, relinquish to the United States any claim which it has to any part of New Mexico.</p>
			<p>5th—RESOLVED, That it is inexpedient to abolish Slavery in the District of Columbia, while that institution continues to exist in the State of Maryland, without the consent of that State, with out the consent of the people of the District, and without just compensation to the owners of slaves within the District.</p>
			<p>6th—RESOLVED, That it is expedient to prohibit within the District the trade in slaves brought into it from States or places beyond the limits of the District, either to be sold therein, as merchandise, or to be transported to other markets without the District of Columbia.</p>
			<p>7th—RESOLVED, That more effectual provision ought to be made by law, according to the requirements of the constitution, for the restitution and delivery of persons bound to service or labor, in any State, who may escape into any other State or Territory of this Union.</p>
			<p>8th—RESOLVED, That Congress has no power to prohibit or obstruct the trade in slaves between the slaveholding States, and that the admission or exclusion of slaves brought from one into another of them, depends exclusively upon their own particular law.</p>
			<p>Oliver &amp; Brother, Printers, 89 Nassau-Street, N. Y.</p>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>